<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Why We Tech on</title><link>http://whywe.tech/</link><description>Recent content in Why We Tech on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://whywe.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Corespondenc Alignment and the REPL</title><link>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/correspondence-alignment-and-the-repl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/correspondence-alignment-and-the-repl/</guid><description>Video games are a REPL with a very rapid feedback loop.</description></item><item><title>Using the Test->Learn REPL For AWS Certs</title><link>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/for-aws-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/for-aws-certs/</guid><description>AWS Cloud Services is a large data object and learning them requires a fat data pipeline straight into your mind. I recently had to upgrade the throughput on that data channel and I want to record here how that happened.
I scheduled my first AWS Exam for a Friday and had been doing the in-course questions and passing at about 80%. Then, on the Wednesday morning before the scheduled exam, I took the BenchPrep official practice exam.</description></item><item><title>Static Sites for Active Documentation</title><link>http://whywe.tech/pro-logic/static-sites-for-active-documentation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:14:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/pro-logic/static-sites-for-active-documentation/</guid><description> Portability ASCII Markdown Folder tree hierarchy navigation Serverless Micropublishing Independent of server archetecture/tech stack Text Transpilation Ingest process all data sources into ASCII word structures Render ASCII word structures into any display format Word-based concept storage and processing Active Notebooks REPL Interactive Data-Info Programming Learning by doing recursivity</description></item><item><title>Why Alien Life Would Be Our Doom</title><link>http://whywe.tech/anti-tech/why-alien-life-would-be-our-doom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/anti-tech/why-alien-life-would-be-our-doom/</guid><description>Here is just another anti-tech screed styled as observation on alien life forms.
If anyone doubts that there is an ideological war against tech, here is yet another example.</description></item><item><title>The Value of Other Users</title><link>http://whywe.tech/other-users/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/other-users/</guid><description>I am reading Judea Pearl&amp;rsquo;s fascinating book &amp;ldquo;The Book of Why&amp;rdquo;, about the cognitive liberation going on in science due to the innovation of causal notation. The mere creation of a new causal notation in science diagrams and notation syntax has revealed a whole new facet about how our minds and actions integrate with scientific outcomes.
In it he tells the story of a scientist who had discovered the Bayesian networks the author developed, but 20 years earlier.</description></item><item><title>Why We Tech</title><link>http://whywe.tech/why-we-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/why-we-tech/</guid><description>Prometheus is tortured for bringing fire, pyrotechnics, down from heaven.
Icarus is punished for inventing human flight.
Adam and Eve are &amp;ldquo;cast out&amp;rdquo; from the Garden of Eden and convicted with &amp;ldquo;original sin&amp;rdquo; for all generations to come, for the crime of tasting of the tree of knowledge.
There is a deep schism between the intellectuals of morality and the intellectuals of technology.
Today this is manifested in the division between the tech departments of academia and the humanities.</description></item></channel></rss>