<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>http://whywe.tech/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://whywe.tech/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Testing to learn and deliberate practice</title><link>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/deliberate-practice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/deliberate-practice/</guid><description>I scheduled my first AWS Exam for a Friday and had been doing the in-course questions and passing at about 80%. Then, on the Wednesday morning before the scheduled exam I took the BenchPrep official practice exam. I scored 30%. There was an elevation of urgency.
Over the next several hours I blocked out all thinking about anything else, as much as that&amp;rsquo;s possible. I was able to eleminate all social media and as much interpersonal communications as possible and isolate my brain to a dedicated task, flushing the cache on almost all other concerns and clearing my plate.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/dimitri-qa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/dimitri-qa/</guid><description>[7/18 7:21 AM] Dimitri Bello Good morning Mark - my name is Dimitri, and i am with the Cloud &amp;amp; IT infrastructure team! Congrats of your recent AWS certification, and i would like to ask you if you have any resource to recommend as practice tests? i am planning to take the solutions architect in the near future!
[8/18 8:28 AM] Mark Stouffer I was taking the exams in order to learn AWS.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/validating-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whywe.tech/posts/testing-to-learn/validating-experience/</guid><description>Validating Experience If you&amp;rsquo;ve used AWS services for any length of time, you have some knowledge about them but you don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly how your knowledge set relates to other people.
To align our understanding of the AWS set of services and systems we can start by looking at what the exam guide lists as knowledge domains for, as an example, the Certified Developer Associate Exam (DVA-C01):
Domain 1 Deployment 22% Deploy written code in AWS using existing CI/CD pipelines, processes, and patterns Deploy applications using Elastic Beanstalk Prepare the application deployment package to be deployed to AWS Deploy serverless applications Domain 2: Security 26% Make authenticated calls to AWS services Implement encryption using AWS services Implement application authentication, and authorization Domain 3: Development with AWS Services 30% Write code for serverless applications Translate functional requirements into application design Implement application design into application code Write code that interacts with AWS services by using APIs, SDKs, and AWS CLI Domain 4: Refactoring 10% Optimize application to best use AWS services and features Migrate existing application code to run on AWS Domain 5: Monitoring and Troubleshooting 12% Write code that can be monitored Perform root cause analysis on faults found in testing or production The percentages are an attempt to quantify the valid knowlege set for a Developer Associate, but they only tell us the portion of the total knowledge set a prospective Developer Associat needs for Deployment.</description></item></channel></rss>